Guide to the Juan E. Méndez Papers, 1980-2017 and undated RL.11330
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Lectures, Teaching, Consultancies, Leadership Roles, 1995-2017
  - Brookings project, 2010-2012; 74 files; approximately 7 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, HTML, THMX, and WEBARCHIVE. Document files in DOC and PDF. Image and graphics file in VML, JPEG, GIF, and PNG.
  - CEJIL, 2010-2012; 15 files; approximately 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in MSG, WEBARCHIVE, XML, HTML, and THMX. Document files in DOC, PDF, and plain text.
  - CELS, 2010-2011; 56 files; approximately 2 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, HTML, THMX, and MSG. Graphics and image files in VML. Document files in DOC, PDF, and PPT.
  - Chile Summer Program 2011, 46 files; approximately 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, HTML, THMX, and WEBARCHIVE. Image and graphics files in VML. Document files in DOC and plain text.
  - CICC, 2010-2011; 65 files; approximately 9 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in PDF and DOC. Web files in XML, HTML, MSG, and THMX. Image and graphics files in VML.
  - CLALS, 2010-2017; 268 files; approximately 22 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in JS, HTML, XML, MSG, THMX, CSS, JSON, and PHP. Document files in DOC, DOCM, plain text, PDF, and RTF. Image, audiovisual, and graphics files in GIF, PNG, JPEG, VML, and FLV. Compressed files in ZIP.
  - Consultative conf on Intl Justice, 2009-2010; 59 files; approximately 3 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, HTML, MSG, and WEBARCHIVE. Image and graphics files in VML. Document files in plain text, PDF, DOC, and RTF.
  - Contacts, 1993; 2 files; approximately 88 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in WordPerfect for MS-DOS.
  - Correspondence, 2009-2012; 1 file; approximately 90 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document file in DOC.
  - Course for prison doctors, 1995-2008; 8151 files; approximately 557 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Contents of CD rom "Course for prison doctors."
    Web files in HTML, PSD, CSS, PE, MAC, and JS. Image and graphics files in JPEG, GIF, PSD, and PNG. Document files in PDF and plain text.
  - Crimes Against Humanity Project, 2009-2011; 393 files; approximately 163 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, MSG, THMX, CSS, and WEBARCHIVE. Image and graphics files in VML, JPEG, and GIF. Document files in PDF, DOC, plain text, PPT, XLS, and RTF.
  - CVT, 2011; 9 files; approximately 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in MSG. Document files in DOC.
  - Detainee Treatment Panel, 2010-2012; 2 files; approximately 90 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in PDF and DOC.
  - Doughty Street Chambers, 2016-2017; 25 files; approximately 5 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in MSG. Document files in DOC, PDF, and XLS.
  - DPLF, 2009-2012; 8 files; approximately 146 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML and THMX. Graphics files in VML.
  - Duke WOLA book award, 2011; 12 files; approximately 147 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, HTML, and THMX. Graphics file in VML.
  - Essex dissertation, 2009; 2 files; approximately 26 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in DOC and plain text.
  - FICJC, 2009; 2 files; approximately 166 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in HTML and WEBARCHIVE.
  - Ford Foundation, 2009-2012; 14 files; approximately 961 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in HTML and WEBARCHIVE. Document files in DOC, PDF, plain text, and RTF.
  - Freedom of Expression, 2009-2013; 8 files; approximately 900 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in PDF and DOC. Web files in XML, MSG, and THMX. Graphics file in VML.
  - GCRtoP, 2009-2014; 131 files; approximately 21 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in PDF, DOC, and plain text. Web files in XML, MSG, HTML, and WEBARCHIVE. Graphics files in JPEG and VML.
  - GI NET, 2010-2012; 33 files; approximately 424 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, MSG, and HTML. Graphics and image files VML, GIF, JPEG, and PNG. Document files in PDF.
  - Global Action to Prevent War, 2011-2012; 4 files; approximately 35 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, HTML, and MSG.
  - Global Rights, 2009; 2 files; approximately 16 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in HTML.
  - Grotius Center project, 2011-2012; 6 files; approximately 258 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in PDF and DOC. Web files in XML, HTML, and MSG.
  - Harald Edelstam Foundation, 2012-2017; 53 files; approximately 22 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in PDF and DOC. Web files in MSG.
  - Hemispheric Daily Briefings, 2016-2017; 3 files; approximately 416 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in MSG.
  - HRW, 2010-2015; 1 file; approximately 42 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
  - IBA, 2009-2017; 2584 files; approximately 249 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, THMX, HTML, MSG, JS, CSS, PHP, WEBARCHIVE, and ASD. Document files in DOC, PDF, PDF/X, plain text, XLS, PPT, and DOT. Graphics and image files in VML, JPEG, GIF, and PNG. Compressed files in ZIP and GZIP.
  - ICHRP, 2012; 4 files; approximately 56 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML and THMX. Graphics file in VML.
  - ICJ, 2016-2017; 20 files; approximately 10 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
  - ICTJ, 2009-2017; 284 files; approximately 9 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in HTML, JS, XML, CSS, MSG, PHP, and MSG. Graphics and image files in JPEG, GIF, VML, and PNG. Document files in plain text, PDF, and DOC.
  - IHL, 2010-2017; 255 files; approximately 18 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in JS, CSS, HTML, JSON, XML, MSG, THMX, and WEBARCHIVE. Graphics and image files in JPEG, PNG, GIF, VML and SVG. Document files in plain text and PDF.
  - IIDH, 2012-2017; 4 files; approximately 2 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in PDF. Web files in MSG.
  - Illinois Holocaust Museum, 2017; 4 files; approximately 9 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
  - ILSP, 2012; 67 files; approximately 25 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in MSG, XML, and THMX. Document files in DOC and PDF. Graphics files in VML. Compressed files in ZIP.
  - Inter-Am System of Protection, 2009-2012; 3 files; approximately 813 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in DOC.
  - International Justice, 2009-2012; 139 files; approximately 12 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in HTML and WEBARCHIVE. Document files in DOC, plain text, PDF, and XLS.
  - Intl Senior Lawyers Project, 2014-2015; 3 files; approximately 361 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in MSG. Document file in PDF.
  - IPS Letelier Moffitt, 2017; 2 files; approximately 328 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
  - IPSI, 2014; 2 files; approximately 148 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
  - Israel Summer Program, 2010-2011; 401 files; approximately 10 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, THMX, and HTML. Graphics and image files in VML, JPEG, and GIF. Document files in DOC, plain text, PDF, XLS, and PPT. Compressed files in GZIP.
  - JEI Nigeria, 2014-2016; 11 files; 4 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
  - John Merck Fund Human Rights Program, 2009; 4 files; approximately 195 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in XLS. Web file in HTML.
  - Justice Empowerment Initiatives, 2014-2016; 3 files; approximately 186 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
  - Kiev, 2012-2015; 292 files; approximately 20 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in JS, MSG, CSS, HTML, and XML. Document files in DOC, PDF, XLS, and plain text. Graphics and image files in GIF, PNG, and JPEG.
  - Letelier Moffitt Selection committee, 2017; 2 files; approximately 180 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web file in MSG and document file in DOC.
  - Museum of Holocaust Committee on Conscience, 2011-2012; 84 files; approximately 7 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, THMX, HTML, and MSG. Document files in DOC and PDF. Graphics and image files in VML, GIF, and PNG.
  - Notre Dame Law School, 2013-2017; 13 files; approximately 1 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in MSG and WEBARCHIVE. Document files in PDF.
  - OSJI, 2009-2016; 444 files; approximately 87 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in MSG, XML, HTML, THMX, CSS, JS, and WEBARCHIVE. Document files in DOC, PDF, PPT, RTF, XLS, and plain text. Graphics and image files in VML, GIF, PNG, and JPEG. Compressed files in ZIP.
  - Oxford, 2004-2012; 854 files; approximately 158 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in DOC, plain text, XLS, RTF, and PDF. Web files in CSS, THMX, XLSX, PPT, WEBARCHIVE, JSON, MSG, HTML, JS, and XML. Graphics and image files in PNG, GIF, JPEG, and VML. Compressed files in EXIF and ZIP.
  - outside boards, 2009-2017; 188 files; approximately 4 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, THMX, HTML, MSG, and WEBARCHIVE. Graphics and image files in VML, JPEG, GIF, and PNG. Document files in PDF, DOC, and plain text. Compressed files in GZIP.
  - Panel Materials, 2003-2013; 44 files; approximately 25 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in PDF and OLECF.
  - Proyecto LGBTI Lam, 2017; 3 files; approximately 628 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
  - Remedies Conference, 2009; 34 files; approximately 6 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in DOC and plain text. Web files in XML, THMX, HTML, and WEBARCHIVE. Graphics and image files in VML.
  - Research Projects and assistance, 2009-2012; 80 files; approximately 2 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Separated Materials
    Web files in XML, HTML, and THMX. Graphics and image files in VML. Document files in DOC, PDF, and plain text.
  - Resumes and Recommendations, 2009-2017; 841 files; approximately 107 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in DOC, PDF, plain text, XLS, and RTF. Web files in MSG, XML, THMX, and HTML. Graphics and image files in VML, and JPEG. Compressed files in ZIP.
  - REvista SUR, 2010-2012; 9 files; approximately 142 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, HTML, and THMX. Document files in DOC.
  - RFK Center for Justice and HR, 2009-2012; 239 files; approximately 9 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, THMX, HTML, and WEBARCHIVE. Document files in DOC, PDF, plain text, and PPT. Graphics and image files VML, GIF, and JPEG.
  - Rothko, 2010-2012; 100 files; approximately 10 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in MSG, XML, THMX, and HTML. Document files in PDF, DOC, and XLS. Graphics and image files in VML and GIF.
  - RtoP Task Force, 2011-2012; 16 files; approximately 2 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in DOC and PDF. Web files in XML, THMX, and HTML. Graphics and image files in GIF, PNG, and VML.
  - Sevane Garibian research pjct on TJ, 2016; 2 files; approximately 109 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Includes web file in MSG and document file in PDF.
  - Speaking Engagements, 2009-2017; 1990 files; approximately 358 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in MSG, JS, XML, THMX, HTML, CSS, WEBARCHIVE, JSON, ASD, and PHP. Graphics, audiovisual, and image files in JPEG, VML, PNG, GIF, ICO, FLV, and BMP. Document files in PDF, DOC, plain text, XLS, and RTF. Compressed files in EXIF and ZIP.
  - Summer Academy, 2008-2017; 278 files; approximately 98 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in MSG, XML, THMX, HTML, JS, CSS, PHP, and JSON. Document files in PDF, DOC, XLS, and plain text. Graphics and image files in PNG, GIF, VML, and JPEG.
  - Transitional Justice, 2009-2017; 8872 files; 593 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in JS, HTML, CSS, MSG, JSON, WEBARCHIVE, WEBP, PHP, XML, ASD, and ASP. Graphics, audiovisual, and image files in GIF, PNG, JPEG, SVP, VML, FLV, and MPEG. Document files in plain text, PDF, DOC, XLS, PPT, and RTF. Compressed files in EXIF and ZIP.
  - UN Global Study on Children Deprived of Liberty, 2016; 3 files; 4 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
  - Universal Rights Group, 2013-2017; 35 files; approximately 7 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in MSG. Document files in DOC and PDF.
  - US accountability, 2009-2012; 3256 files; approximately 137 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in JS, XML, THMX, HTML, CSS, MSG, WEBARCHIVE, PHP, JSON, and WEBP. Graphics, image, and audiovisual files in JPEG, VML, GIF, PNG, and FLV. Document files in plain text, DOC, XLS, and PDF. Compressed files in EXIF.
  - US policy towards Latin America, 2009-2012; 3 files; approximately 283 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in PDF and plain text. Web files in WEBARCHIVE.
  - Vance Center, 2014; 6 files; approximately 188 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, HTML, THMX, and MSG. Document file in DOC.
  - War Crimes Prosecution Watch, 2009-2012; 8 files; approximately 519 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in DOC. Web files in XML, HTML, THMX, and MSG.
  - War Crimes Research Office WCL, 2012; 8 files; approximately 519 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
  - Washington College of Law, 2010-2018; 4512 files; approximately 598 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in JS, HTML, MSG, CSS, XML, THMX, WEBARCHIVE, PHP, JSON, and ASD. Image and graphics files in PNG, GIF, JPEG, VML, JPEG, SVG, and TIFF. Document files in DOC, plain text, PDF, XLS, RTF, and PPT.
  - witness, 2011-2012; 12 files; approximately 18 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in MSG, XML, HTML, and THMX. Document files in PDF.
  - Womens Link Worldwide, 2009-2011; 5 files; approximately 48 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML and THMX. Image and graphics files in JPEG and VML.
- Personal Files, 2004-2014; 7
  - indemnizaciones exilo, 2007-2014; 32 files; approximately 8 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
  - Administrative, 2009-2011; 17 files; approximately 12 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in HTML and WEBARCHIVE. Document files in DOC and PDF.
  - Photos, 2004-2012; 15 files; approximately 129 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Image and graphics files in JPEG, BMP, and DB. Compressed files in EXIF.
  - Soledad, 2009; 11 files; approximately 5 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in WEBARCHIVE, and HTML. Document files in DOC and plain text.